Lawrence Gipe Operation Streamline Sketches, circa 2012-2014
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Lawrence Gipe Operation Streamline Sketches, circa 2012-2014
MS 524
Gipe, Lawrence, 1962-
This collection contains sketches by Lawrence Gipe created in pencil on paper. The materials document trials of detainees who are accused of illegal immigration into the United States as part of the Operation Streamline program.
1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Lawrence Gipe is an American painter and Assistant Professor of 2D Studies at the University of Arizona School Of Art. Gipe also works closely with the End Streamline Coalition which is a group of organizations, community groups, and individuals dedicated to ending the Operation Streamline program in Tucson, AZ. This program began in the United States Border Patrol's Del Rio sector in west Texas and spread across the United States – Mexico border. Operation Streamline mandates that undocumented immigrants crossing the border be prosecuted through the federal criminal justice system rather than the civil immigration system as had been the previous procedure. Trials under the Operation Streamline program have been criticized for their expediency, excessive prison sentences, and for prosecuting detainees en masse. This project was funded in part by the Confluencenter for Creative Inquiry at the University of Arizona.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series
Series I:Sketches, circa 2012-2014
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of sketches done is pencil by Lawrence Gipe which document trials of detainees accused of illegal immigration into the United States as part of the Operation Streamline program. Items 11 and 19 have sketches on both sides of the piece. The side that is signed by Lawrence Gipe is considered to be the front of the item. Items 33-37 can be viewed in the Special Collections reading Room.
Access Terms
Gipe, Lawrence, 1962-.
Illegal aliens – Arizona.
Illegal aliens – Government policy – United States.
Political activists – United States.
Courtroom illustrations
Container List
- Sketches, circa 2012-2014
  Series contains courtroom sketches by Lawrence Gipe done in pencil on paper. Titles have been derived from Lawrence Gipe's website and from inscriptions on the works.
  - 6 Children – All American Citizens, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Caught Crossing in Douglas was Attempting to Visit His Newly-Born Daughter, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Shackled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Given Your Criminal History, You're not Welcome Here – Judge, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 7)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Citizen of Guatemala, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Six Legal Children in the U.S., circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Recto - Untitled, Verso – Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 14)
  - 180 Days…You Can Quit Paying Attention Now, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Sentencing, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Recto - Untitled, Verso – Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Lawyers, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Untitled, circa 2012-2014 (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 25 (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 28)
  - I Don't Want to go to Jail for 60 Days… You Lost Control – Stay out of the System – Stay Home… Why am I getting 60 Days When I've Only Been Caught Twice?, 2014 June 25 (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 25 (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Untitled, circa 2014 September (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Dock (1), circa 2014 September (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Leaving After Sentencing, circa 2014 September (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Untitled, circa 2014 September (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Untitled, 2014 June 23 (Box 1, Item 37)